Like to say welcome brothers and sisters
to another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep. Brother James. Yes,
sir.
And God spoke all these words saying, "I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image or any
likeness of any thing that is in heaven
above or that is in the earth beneath or
that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me and keep
my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain.
Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy. Six days shalt thou labor and do
all thy work. But the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it thou
shalt not do any work. Thou nor thy son
nor thy daughter, thy man servant nor
thy maid servant nor thy cattle nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea and all that in them is
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hollowed it.
Honor thy father and thy mother that thy
days may be long upon the land which the
Lord thy God giveth thee. Thou shalt not
kill. Thou shalt not commit adultery.
Thou shalt not steal. Thou shalt not
bear false witness against thy neighbor.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
house. Thou shalt not covet thy
neighbor's wife
nor his man servant nor his maid servant
nor his ox nor his ass nor anything that
is thy neighbor's. I read Exodus
20:1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
Amen.
So here on question and answer you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also keep
in mind that this is a live stream so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you keep them to a two
scripture maximum. But let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. We've got brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
Brother Julius. Good evening, everybody.
Brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother James.
Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
Brother Shawn.
And we have the guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell. And sister Deborah,
before we get started, we just want to
remind everybody that we are now this
Saturday will be in part three of our
black history spiritual death and
resurrection. So please feel free to
join us at 12:00 noon.
All right, sister Deborah, what is our
first question of the evening?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Humility says, "I'm confused.
The Bible says that the dead knows
nothing. So in Samuel, who actually
showed up and spoke to Saul when he
visited that witch?"
All right. So who actually showed up to
to Saul when he went to go visit that
witch? Brother Dre, can you help with
some of the confusion? Yes. As [snorts]
you said, the scripture says the dead
know nothing. Let's go read that. Let's
go to Ecclesiastes 9 and read verse 5.
Okay.
Ecclesiastes
9 and verse 5 says,
"For the living know that they shall
die.
But the dead know not anything.
Neither have they any more reward for
the memory of them is forgotten."
So the dead don't know anything. So if
they don't know nothing, they can't say
anything.
And they have no more a reward, the
scripture says, right? And let's go
verify that one more time. Let's go to
Job 14 and read verse 12.
14 and verse 12. Go ahead when you get
it, brother.
Okay.
Job 14:12 says,
"So man lieth down and riseth not till
the heavens be no more.
They shall not awake nor be raised out
of their sleep."
So you're asking the question about
Samuel, who was that that was raised?
He went and sought a a familiar spirit
from a witch. Let's see what the Bible
says about that. Let's go to Deuteronomy
18.
Deuteronomy 18
and pick it up at verse 10. When you get
there, go ahead, brother.
Okay. Deuteronomy 18:10
says,
"There shall not be found among you
anyone that maketh his son or his
daughter to pass through the fire or
that uses divination or an observer of
times or an enchanter or a witch." Go
ahead.
"Or a charmer or a consulter with
familiar spirits or a wizard or a
necromancer."
A familiar spirit or a wizard or a
necromancer,
one who supposedly is bringing up the
dead. Verse 12.
"For all that do these things are an
abomination unto the Lord.
And because of these abominations, the
Lord thy God doeth drive them out from
before thee." Now let's see what the
Bible says Samuel did. First Chronicles
10, we're just going to read verse 13.
When you get there, go ahead, brother.
First Chronicles 10 and verse 13 says,
"So Saul died for his transgression
which he committed against the Lord,
even against the word of the Lord which
he kept not, and also for asking counsel
of one that had a familiar spirit to
inquire of it." Notice it didn't say
that Saul died for his transgression for
talking to Samuel.
He died
for committing for his transgression and
committing
that he committed against the Lord
which he and and against the word of the
Lord which he kept not and asking
counsel of one that had a familiar
spirit. Didn't say one that had Samuel.
One that had a familiar spirit to
inquire of it.
So the answer is that was not Samuel cuz
we read in Job that the dead don't know
nothing.
And and in Ecclesiastes 9:5. That's all
I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
And we definitely hope that that shines
some light on humility. All right. Let's
move on to our next question.
Next one. E. Robin says, "I was reading
Genesis 49:9-12.
Is this about Judah and Jesus?"
All right. Now Genesis 49
and verse
9 through 12. Is this about Judah and
Jesus? Brother Julius, is it?
Julius, you're on mute.
The answer is is yes. It's talking about
the tribe of Judah and Jesus who will
come out of the tribe of Judah.
Let's read. But this time
brother James, pick it up at Genesis
49:8.
Okay.
Genesis 49:8 says, "Judah, thou art he
whom thy brethren shall praise. Thy hand
shall be in the neck of thine enemies.
Thy father's children shall bow down
before thee.
Judah is Judah is a lion's whelp. From
the prey, my son, thou art gone up.
He stooped down. He couched as a lion
and as an old lion. Who shall rouse him
up?" Continue.
"The scepter shall not depart from Judah
nor a lawgiver from between his feet
until Shiloh come.
And unto him shall the gathering of the
people be. And when he come, what he
going to do? When Jesus come on the
scene,
what are you going to do at verse 11?
Binding his foal unto the vine.
And his ass colt unto the choice vine.
He washed his garments in wine, and his
clothes in the blood of grapes. And that
was the crucifixion. Let's back this up.
He coming on a foal of an ass. Matthew
the 21st chapter.
Matthew chapter 21. Read a little
quicker, James. Verse one. Matthew 21
and verse one. When you get it, go
ahead, brother.
>> Can I intervene?
Can I intervene? Yes, sir. Yes.
Okay.
Revelation 19 chapter.
When Jesus was a fighting against the
nation.
And his garments
red with the blood of the nation. Yep.
And he tell you all there he had come
from uh Teman.
And uh he had treaded the wine press.
His garments was stained
with the blood. Yep. Like grapes.
That blood uh
that he washes his garments in with the
blood of men during the time of the war
of Armageddon.
Yes, sir.
But the whole thing is about Judah and
Jesus. Just like Jesus Jesus
uh just like uh brother Julius said. I
just wanted to throw that in there. But
go ahead.
Thank you, guest caller. Matthew 21.
Picking it up at verse one, James. When
you get it, go ahead.
And when they drew nigh unto Jerusalem,
and were come to Bethphage, unto the
mount of olives, then sent Jesus two
disciples.
Saying unto them, go into the village
over against you, and straightway ye
shall find an ass tied, and a colt with
her. Loose them, and bring them unto me.
Go ahead. And if any man say ought unto
you, ye shall say, the Lord hath need of
them. And straightway he will send them.
You see how you can see that this is
plainly talking about Jesus. Finish it,
brother.
All this was done, that it might be
fulfilled which was spoken by the
prophet, saying, Tell ye the daughter of
Zion, Behold, thy king cometh unto thee,
meek and sit
Thy king cometh unto thee, meek and
sitting upon an ass, and a colt the foal
of an ass. And that was prophesied in
Zechariah nine and verse nine. You can
read that on your own. So, the the
answer to the question is talking about
Jesus, the tribe of Judah, and it's
talking about Jesus.
That's all I got.
And thanks again, guest caller.
All right. We hope that answered your
question there as we continue to move on
to our next.
Next one, Humility asks, Did the Lord
show up as a giant?
There are multiple verses that seem to
hint at this, such as Exodus 33,
Zechariah 14 verse four, Isaiah 40 verse
12, First Kings eight
verse 27, and others.
All right. So, um
Brother Jerome, did the Lord show up as
a giant? And we're also asking Humility
to be mindful to please keep our
scriptures to two maximum. But go ahead,
my brother Jerome.
Um
Well, let's go read um some of those
verses
that you gave. Um
I don't I don't think you gave a verse
for that Exodus, so I don't know which
verse you're drawing from on that one.
Can you do the Zechariah 14 and 14,
which was the next one? Mhm.
Zechariah 14 and four says, And his feet
shall stand in that day upon the mount
of olives, which is before Jerusalem on
the east, and the mount of olives shall
cleave in the midst thereof toward the
east, and toward the west. And there
shall be a very great valley, and half
of the mountain shall remove toward the
north, and half of it toward the south.
Yeah, it's not giving uh no indication
that we can draw from to determine his
size there.
But we know he going when he hit that
Mount of Olives, he going to hit it with
some power. You know, but it don't give
a size there, so we're not going to
speculate.
Um the next one you gave was 40 and 12.
Isaiah 40 and 12.
Mhm. That says,
Who hath measured the waters in the
hollow of his hand,
and meted out heaven with the span, and
comprehended the dust of the earth in a
measure, and weighed the mountains in
scales, and the hills in a balance?
Yeah, once again, we we can't speculate,
um but by his knowledge,
he's able to do all that we read in that
verse. It's through knowledge.
It's not necessarily about how big his
hands were, but that he had the wisdom
and knowledge to do what's written in
that verse. That's really what that's
talking about there. Okay?
Uh and you gave First Kings chapter
eight verse 27.
First Kings. First Kings chapter eight.
And verse 27 says,
But will God indeed dwell on the earth?
Behold, the heaven and heaven of heavens
cannot contain thee. How much less this
house that I have built?
Yeah, and and
when you consider um when the Lord
returns, the Lord Jesus, when he
returns,
he going choose to be
a size to actually dwell in a house.
That's going to be built uh
in Jerusalem. But he's a spirit being. I
I wanted to read back read that. He He
the creator, so
let's go read that uh Saint John chapter
four verse 24.
Okay.
John four
and 24 says,
God is a spirit, and they that worship
him must worship him in spirit and in
truth. Yeah, so
God, he is the creator of heaven and
earth. He created everything that's in
the heavens and on this earth. And if he
choose to be large, he can do that. And
if he choose to be a regular size man,
he can do that. And if he choose to
dwell in a house that's going to be
built for him for eternity, he can do
that. And whatever size he choose,
that's his choice, you know. But no,
it's not about how big or how small he
is, okay? Cuz we can't read that, so
we're not going to speculate. That's all
I got on it.
I'd like to I'd like to throw in
something.
Okay.
>> Yes, sir.
There ain't nothing in these scriptures
that indicate that the Lord was a giant.
All right. Yeah. I don't
How you could come to that?
Yeah.
You understood the scripture that the
giant going to sit on David's throne?
Giant going to sit in the temple?
I don't know where you got that from,
but it didn't get it from the Bible. And
that scripture there have nothing to do
with the giant with a giant. Yeah.
That's all I want to say. Yeah.
All right.
Thank you for that add-on as we continue
to move on.
Moving on. Attica Masala asks,
Scripturally speaking, when does time
end?
So, scripturally speaking, guest caller,
when does time come to an end?
Well,
scripturally speaking, time don't come
to an end. That's right.
>> What happen is
man come to an end.
And let's look at something here. You
know,
uh uh uh
Let's see when man's time come to an
end.
Let's go into
uh uh uh
Revelation the 20th chapter.
Because man's time come to the end at
the end of the thousand years that Jesus
ruled this earth.
Revelation 20.
We're going to read from four to six,
then we're going to skip down.
Okay.
Revelation 20 verse four through six
says,
And I saw thrones, and they sat upon
them, and judgment was given unto them.
And I saw the souls of them that were
beheaded for the witness of Jesus, and
for the word of God.
And which had not worshipped the beast,
neither his image, neither had received
his mark upon their foreheads or in
their hands, and they lived and reigned
with Christ a thousand years.
But the rest of
the dead lived not again until the
thousand years were finished. This is
the first resurrection.
Now, people that come up in the and
finish that. Finish it.
Blessed and holy is he that hath part in
the first resurrection. On such the
second death hath no power. But they
shall be priests of God and of Christ,
and shall reign with him a thousand
years.
Now, that's the first resurrection.
Now, the last resurrection is going to
be is when you have a white throne
judgment.
So, let's skip down
verse
uh
12 and continue. 12 to 15.
Okay.
Verse 12 says, "And I saw the dead,
small and great, stand before God. And
the books were opened, and another book
was opened, which is the book of life.
And the dead were judged out of those
things which were written in the books
according to their works."
Go ahead. "And the sea gave up the dead
which were in it, and death and hell
delivered up the dead which were in
them. And they were judged every man
according to their works."
"And death and hell were cast into the
lake of fire. This is the second death."
"And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life was cast into the lake
of fire."
All right. That terminated man, and that
terminated death. That is when man's
time came to an end. Go to 1 Corinthians
15 and we're going to read uh verse 24
to 26.
Okay.
>> going to skip.
1 Corinthians 15:24-26
says, "Then cometh the end, when he
shall have delivered up the kingdom to
God, even the Father. When he shall have
put down all rule and all authority and
power."
"For he must reign till he put all
enemies under his feet." "The last enemy
that shall be destroyed is death."
Now, skip down and read verse 28.
"And when all things shall be subdued
unto him, then shall the Son also
himself be subject unto him that put all
things under him, that God may be all in
all."
So, that is the end of man's time.
When Jesus ruled ends it in a thousand
years.
And after you had the white throne
judgment, then and then there will be no
more
mortals. Even the people in the lake of
fire will be immortals.
And everything left after that is God
and whatever
else that the people in the lake of fire
call with the angels that rebelled
against him.
So, that's when the end of the end of
the thousand year millennium period and
the white throne judgment. That's all I
got to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we continue to move on to
our next.
Moving on, Zion says, "In John 8:20,
it says God will not help the evil doer.
Should we
example, like someone constantly going
to prison, then calls and asks for money
to be put on their books?"
All right. Let's go and see what John
8:20 says.
John 8:20.
It says says, "God will not help the
evil doer." Go ahead, brother.
"These words spake Jesus in the
treasury, as he taught in the temple."
"And no man laid hands on him, for his
hour was not yet come."
All right. So, that verse there has
nothing to do when you're speaking in
terms of a evil doer.
But me and brother Jerome was having a
discussion and he believed you meant Job
8:20.
So, let's go there.
Job 8:20.
Okay.
Job 8:20 says, "Behold, God will not
cast away a perfect man, neither will he
help the evil doers." Yeah, so that
might be what you mean right there when
you talked about the evil doers there.
But skip down to verse 22 and read that.
"They that hate thee shall be clothed
with shame." "And the dwelling place of
the wicked shall come to naught."
So, all of those that hate the the law
of God and what he stand for and doing
what's right when time run out, yeah,
he's not going to help the evil doers.
He's going to help them to punish
punishment forever.
But let's go into that Psalms 37, too.
Psalms 37.
Because like the Lord say, while there's
life, hey, you should repent and try and
get right. Don't let time run out on
you.
You don't want to die with that wicked
report card. Psalm 37 and pick it up at
that verse 27 and 28, brother. Go ahead.
"Depart from evil and do good
[clears throat] and dwell forevermore."
So, this is the Lord saying you got to
depart from evil
and do good and dwell forevermore. Go
ahead.
"For the Lord for the Lord loveth
judgment and forsaketh not his saints."
"They are preserved forever, but the
seed of the wicked shall be cut off."
Which is also evil doers. Skip down and
read 38. Go ahead.
"But the transgressors
shall be destroyed together." "The end
of the wicked shall be cut off."
So, hey, as long as you have life and
you're trying to strive to do what's
right, even if you're evil and you
repent, and the Lord forgive you, hey,
you got a shot at the kingdom just like
everybody else.
But as far as you're asking about
somebody going to prison and and asking
for money and you putting money on their
books, that is your choice. That's your
personal choice if
if you want to do that or no.
But that's all I got.
All right. We're going to leave it right
there, Sister Deborah, with our next
question as well as a time check.
Yes, the time is 7:57.
Uh Susie asks, "Will all Israel go to
the wilderness or will some get left
behind?" "From my understanding," she
says, "all will go to the wilderness and
then be purged. But then I hear that
some will be left." "Will the
unbelieving Israel be left behind?
Please explain."
All right. So, guest caller, when it
pertains to the wilderness, they got
quite a bit in that question. Can you
shed some light?
Look,
it's going to be just like it was when
Israel come out of Egypt. Not one
Israelite is going to be left behind.
We're going to Deuteronomy 30
and read verses 1 through 4.
Okay. Deuteronomy 30
verse 1 through 4 says,
"And it shall come to pass, when all
these things are come upon thee, the
blessing and the curse, which I have set
before thee, and thou shalt call them to
mind among all the nations, whither the
Lord thy God has driven thee."
"And shalt return unto the Lord thy God,
and shalt obey his voice according to
all that I command thee this day."
"Thou, and thy children, with all thine
heart, and with all thine soul."
"That then the Lord thy God will turn
thy
thy captivity, and have compassion upon
thee, and and will return, and gather
thee from all the nations, whither the
Lord thy God have scattered thee."
"If if any of thine be driven out unto
the outmost parts of heaven, from thence
will the Lord thy God gather thee, and
from thence he will fetch thee."
Now, did it tell you right there? That
alone tell you that he's going to gather
everybody. He said even from all the
nation where you've been scattered, even
the most outmost part. In other words,
the most remote. Ain't nobody never
heard of. God know you there. Go to
Isaiah 11.
Read 1 and skip down and read 10 through
12.
Yeah.
Isaiah 1
11. Oh, Isaiah 11. I'm sorry.
Isaiah 11:1
says, "And there shall come forth a rod
out of the stem of Jesse, and a branch
shall grow out of his roots."
Now, skip down to verse 10 and read the
12. Okay. Verse 10 says, "And in that
day, there shall be a root of Jesse,
which shall stand for it ensign of the
people. To it shall the Gentiles seek,
and his rest shall be glorious."
"And it shall come to pass in that day,
that the Lord shall set his hand again
the second time to recover the remnant
of his people, which shall be left from
Assyria, and from Egypt, and from
Pathros, and from Cush, and from Elam,
and from Shinar, and from Hamath, and
from the isles of the sea."
"And he shall set up an ensign for the
nations, and shall assemble the outcast
of Israel, and gather together the
dispersed of Judah from the four corners
of the earth."
Now, that covers every every area. You
feel that was the last of it? Yes.
Let's go to Isaiah 27 read verse 12.
Isaiah 27 and verse 12 says,
"And it shall come to pass in that day,
that the Lord shall beat off from the
channel of the river unto the stream of
Egypt, and ye shall be gathered one by
one, oh ye children of Israel."
Now, when he said gathered one by one,
that mean if you one Israelite in a
remote country and any other Israelite,
he going to get you, too.
So, everybody goes to the wilderness.
What?
Everybody don't go to the land. So,
let's go to Ezekiel 20 chapter and start
reading around verse 30.
And we going to read quickly.
Okay.
Ezekiel 20 and verse 30 says,
"Wherefore, say unto the house of
Israel, thus saith the Lord God, are ye
polluted after the manner of your
fathers, and commit ye whoredom after
their abominations?
For when ye offer your gifts, when ye
make your sons to pass through the fire,
ye pollute yourselves with all your
idols, even until this day.
And shall I be inquired of you, oh house
of Israel? As I live, saith the Lord
God, I will not be inquired of by you.
Great.
>> And that And that which cometh into your
mind shall not be at all that ye say,
"We will be as the heathen, as the
families of the countries to serve wood
and stone."
As I live As I liveth, saith the Lord
God, surely with a mighty hand and with
a stretched out arm and with fury poured
out, will I rule over you.
And I will bring you out from the people
and will gather you out of the countries
wherein ye are scattered with a mighty
hand and with a stretched out arm and
with fury poured out.
And I will bring you into the wilderness
of the people, and there will I plead
with you face to face, like as I pleaded
with your fathers in the wilderness of
the land of Egypt, so will I plead with
you, saith the Lord God.
And I will cause you to pass under the
rod, and I will bring you into the bond
of the covenant. And I will purge out
from among you the rebels with them that
transgress against me.
I will bring them forth out of the
country where they sojourn, and they
shall not enter into the land of Israel,
and ye shall know that I am the Lord.
So, now, the Lord is not going to leave
one Israelite nowhere.
But, as far as the unbelievers are
concerned and the rebels, he going to
leave them behind, though, but he going
to leave them behind in the wilderness
dead.
Like he did your fathers that didn't
believe.
You ready? Yeah. 40 years until all of
them unbelievers died off.
Yeah.
It won't be no different.
So, not one Israelite going to be left
in any other nation. Everybody going
back. But, you going But, the one But,
everybody not going to get in the land.
Like I said before, they going to be
left behind, all right.
As corpses in the wilderness. That's all
I have to say. [clears throat]
Mhm.
All right. We hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one, Melvin Powell says, "I went to
a Lutheran church for a loved one
funeral, and they offered communion.
Does the Bible say anything about taking
communion?"
All right. Does the Bible say anything
about taking communion or taking
communion even also at a funeral?
Brother Julius. Absolutely not.
Absolutely not. Remember, the Lutheran
churches are offshoot or one of the
daughters of the Catholic church.
There are 76 references in the Bible
about Passover.
Now, what they call uh communion, they
call it when they take the bread and the
wine, they call it um Eucharist, they
call it sacrament, they call it
communion. But, it's the same thing,
which represents the bread and the wine,
but it is nowhere written in the Bible
communion. It is called a Passover. Now,
uh in the Lutheran church, they do it
weekly.
In the Catholic church, they do it They
take mass daily.
So, therefore,
let's go to Leviticus the 23rd chapter
and see what the Lord calls the bread
and the wine.
Leviticus the 23rd chapter,
notice they when they use that at the
Lutheran at their funeral at the
Lutheran church, they're offering you
communion.
When should the Passover be taken?
One verse, Leviticus 23 and 5. What the
book say?
In the 14th day of the first month at
even is the Lord's Passover. Not
communion, the Passover, which is eaten
with uh unleavened bread and wine.
So, now, we got us a month,
we got us a day of the month,
and we got us
the time of year.
In the first month and the 14th day of
the month and the time of day, which is
sundown, the Passover is to be taken and
never ever communion. That's why Jesus
kept the Passover with his disciples in
the 14th day on the first month at
evening.
That's all I got, brother Cornell.
All right. Yes, sir.
And also, we know, brother, Christ our
Passover is sacrificed for us. That's
right.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to keep moving.
Moving on. Gloria Jose asks, "Are there
different sections in the lake of fire
or one section for all who ends up
there?"
All right. So,
brother Jerome, is there like, you know,
small, medium, extra hot in the lake of
fire?
>> [laughter]
>> Well, according to your question, you we
can't read where sections
in the lake of fire.
But, we can read where it's a it's it's
going to be a gulf, that we can read.
So, let's go to that
um
Luke 16.
And we going to read verse 23 through
26.
Okay.
Luke 16 verse 23 says,
"And in hell he lift up his eyes, being
in torments, and seeth Abraham afar off,
and Lazarus in his bosom.
And he cried and said, "Father Abraham,
have mercy on me, and send Lazarus, that
he may dip the tip of his finger in
water and cool my tongue, for I am
tormented in this flame."
Mhm. But But, Abraham said, "Son,
remember that thou in thy lifetime
receiveth thy good things, and likewise
Lazarus evil things. But, now he is
comforted, and thou art tormented.
And besides all this, between us and you
there is a great gulf fixed, so that
they which would pass from hence to you
and not, neither can they pass to us
that would come from thence." Yeah. So,
it talk about a gulf, it don't talk
about sections. That's all I got.
Can I throw something in there, Cornell?
Yes, sir.
Go to Revelation the 20th chapter.
Okay.
And when you get it, read one verse.
Verse 15.
"And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life was cast into the lake
of fire."
There are no sections.
Either way it go, and if it was a
section If it was a section, you still
in the lake of fire.
Nothing comforting about that. That's
all I got.
So, good question indeed, but the pain
is going to be the same across the
board. Worms eating on you and fire
burning you up for eternity.
There you go.
All right. We hope that answered your
question as we continue to keep moving.
Moving on. This comment might be funny
as, "Which history book, dictionary,
etc.
show that Egypt means black? I would
love to be able to show people this when
I'm
when I'm talking about black history,
but I can't find it anywhere."
All right. Well, get your pen and paper
as brother Julius sheds some light.
All right.
Let's I I found this clipping here. We
have a clipping here, and this is from
the Scofield Bible, which is still a
King James Bible version.
Look what it says here. I hope you can
see this. I'm going to read it to you.
Can y'all see that?
It's highlighted in yellow. What do it
say, James?
I can't I can't see that.
It says, Egypt
Egypt black. Black. Egypt black. Some
people call it uh Kemet, the land of
Kemet,
which is the land of our black. They
named it after land, but it's really the
people. Now, you say you can't find in
the book. We found it in the book.
This is
the Zondervan Compact Bible Dictionary.
And it And it tells you
that
Let's look. And then if you look up
under Ham cuz Egypt is in the land of
Ham.
Right there in the land of Ham. Now, I'm
going to read this to you
out of this out of the same source
the Zondervan Bible Dictionary, but I
got another source. I'm going to read it
out of out of it to you. Now,
this is Zondervan Bible Dictionary.
The same book
under Ham, but we had it highlighted for
you.
And it says right here
You want me to read it, Julius? Yeah, it
says I'm going to read
I'm going to read it, James. Okay.
>> It says Ham, the youngest son of Noah
born probably about 96 years before the
flood and one of the eight persons to
live through the flood. He became the
progenitor of the dark races.
Not the Negroes, but the Egyptians.
Notice what it said, the dark races. The
The Egyptians,
Ethiopians,
Libyans,
and Canaanites.
So now,
here's another source.
This is my my set of encyclopedia. This
is Collier's Encyclopedia volume 11
dated 1973.
That's why you got to get the older
books.
Here's a second witness
under Ham.
Under Ham.
It says in the Old Testament the second
son of Noah according to biblical trans
tradition, Ham was the progenitor It
says here of one of the three great
races of the world, but we read in the
Bible Dictionary that it said the dark
races.
Now, the etymology of the name Ham It
says the land refers to Egypt. Okay?
Refers to Egypt. On this hypothesis, the
literal meaning of Ham, like that of
Kimit, would be black.
Would be black. Okay?
Uh
the blackness
in the Delta region rather in the
darkness of the skin of the inhabitants
of Africa. That's who the dark races
like just like the book says. Here's my
third source. This is my other set of
encyclopedia. World Scope volume six
under under ancient ancient Egypt. Got
the picture of King Tut and everything.
Look black to me. So now, it says the
ancient Egyptians called their country
Kimit which means black.
But who did the Lord compare his people
Israel to?
Who did the Lord compare his people to?
To the ancient
Ethiopians. It is telling you in
Jeremiah, but we got it right here.
Ethiopia.
Ethiopia which come from the Greek word
Aethiop.
And it says region of burnt faces.
Region
of burnt faces.
When the Greeks saw conquer Ethiopia
which the Greek name is Aethiop from
which you get the word Ethiopia. Can Can
a brother One of you brothers find that
Jeremiah for me? Are you not as the
Ethiopians unto me, oh house of Israel?
It's Amos 9 and 7. Amos 9 and 7. Amos 9
and 7.
>> What is it?
>> It's Amos 9 and 7. Okay, get that ready.
But the word Aethiop or Ethiopia or
Aethiop means burnt faces.
Still in the land of in the continent of
Africa.
So now, read that
uh
to me for me.
Read that for me
James. Amos 9 and 7 says, "Are ye not as
children of the Ethiopians unto me, oh
children of Israel?" saith the Lord.
"Have not I brought up Israel out of the
land of Egypt and the Philistines from
Caphtor and the Syrians from Cur?"
So now, what the world has been accepted
is because they look at the land of
Egypt today, they see Arabs.
How did the Arabs get into
which are Ishmaelites? How did they get
into Egypt's land?
How come they don't look like none of
their artifacts?
You got Rome today, pictures of the
Romans. You got pictures of the Greeks,
Alexander the Great.
How come the people in the land of Egypt
are not black? Because since the history
books will tell you since the 7th
century
Egypt has been an Arab nation through
the conquest of Islam.
So, you got to look in the right places
and you can read You got to get you a
good old Bible that's got the real
information in it as opposed to these
new dictionaries and new Bibles and new
encyclopedia which hides the real
identity of Egypt which means black.
Just like Aethiop or Ethiopia means
burnt faces.
That's all I got. Anybody want to add to
that?
Yeah, can can I add Genesis 10 and 6?
Read that.
>> There you go, Drake. Thank you. Because
we talking about Ham's
child which is Mizraim which is another
name for Egypt. Right, that is the real
name of Egypt, Mizraim.
All right.
Thank you, brothers for that. And if you
show that to them,
we hope that they have eyes to see.
Let's move on to our next one, sister
Dev.
Next one. Robert Dodge says, "I have
sought all the gift or gifts God blessed
me with to bless others,
but
to no avail. Is it possible that I
that I'm just not aware of such a gift
or gifts?" Brother Julius, what about
the gifts? Uh let's go
to
1 Corinthians chapter 12.
You have the gift. You may not
understand it, but we going to show you
the greatest gift that you could have.
Let's go to 1 Corinthians the 12th
chapter, brother James, and read We
going to read verses 7 to 11 quickly.
When you get it, go ahead, brother.
But the manifestation of the spirit is
given to every man to profit with all.
Uh-huh. For to one is given by the
spirit the word of wisdom, to another
the word of knowledge by the same
spirit. Yes. To another faith by the
same spirit, All these are gifts. All
these are considered gifts. Go ahead.
to another the gifts of healing by the
same spirit. You got healers out here.
Go ahead.
To another the working of miracles, to
another prophecy. The gift of prophecy
prophecy. Go ahead. To another
discerning of spirits.
It's another divers kinds of tongues.
Exactly. To another Let me straighten
that out. That means different types of
languages. Go ahead.
To another the interpretation of
tongues. Uh-huh.
But all these worketh that one and the
selfsame spirit dividing to every man
severally as he will. Now, these are
considered the gifts under works. Now,
let me show you the other type of gift.
Ephesians chapter 4 quickly.
Two verses there. Ephesians chapter 4.
And when you get there, my brother
James, let's read verses 8 and then we
going to read 11 and 12. Ephesians 4 and
8. Go ahead.
Wherefore he saith, "When he ascended up
on high, he led captivity captive and
gave gifts unto men." Yes.
Now, that he ascended, what is it
>> to verse 11. Skip down to verse 11,
brother. Go ahead. And he gave some
apostles and some prophets and some
evangelists and some pastors and
teachers. Now, these gifts are
positions.
But let me show you the greatest gift
that you could have and that you should
ask for.
John 14 and verse 15.
You get this gift You get this gift when
you love Jesus.
John 14 and 15 says,
"If ye love me, keep my commandments.
Uh-huh.
And I will pray the Father and he shall
give you another comforter that he may
abide with you forever." So now, you
love Jesus, keep his commandments, be
baptized in his name,
repent first, and then he going to give
you the gift of the Holy Ghost. Go
ahead.
"And the spirit of truth whom the world
whom the world cannot receive because it
seeth him not, neither knoweth him, but
ye know him for he dwelleth with you and
shall be in you."
My last place. That is the Holy the gift
of the Holy Ghost. Okay? That's the word
of God, understanding of the word of God
in this context. My last place, Acts 2
and 38.
This is the greatest gift that you could
ask for.
Acts 2 and 38. What the book say?
Then Peter said unto them, "Repent and
be baptized every one of you in the name
of Jesus Christ for the remission of
sins."
So, you have to repent. Go ahead. And ye
shall receive the gift of the Holy
Ghost.
>> And that's what we read in James John 4
John 14.
The gift of the Holy Ghost, the
understanding of the word of God. That
is what you could use to share with
other people, the word of God, my
brother and sisters. Anybody want to add
to that?
All right. We hope that answered your
question and stay strong and get that
gift of eternal life. All right. Our
next question, Sister Deborah.
Next one, Anil Dang asked, "Will it be
heard
the sound of all seven trumpets
described in the Book of Revelations or
only the last trumpet, the seventh?"
All right. So, in Revelations, will you
be able to hear all of the trumpets or
just the last trumpet, guest caller?
I'm sure it's all of all of the
trumpets.
Otherwise, why would they be blown?
Right.
>> an example this way.
Let's go into
Exodus 20th chapter.
We're going to read 1 through 3.
And then we're going to read 15
through 18.
Okay. Exodus 20:1-3 says,
"And God spake all these words, saying,
'I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have no other gods before me.
Then for
then verse That was 15, correct?
Yes.
"Thou shalt not steal. Thou shalt not
bear false witness against thy neighbor.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
house, thou shalt not covet thy
neighbor's wife, nor his manservant, nor
his maidservant, nor his ox, nor his
ass, nor anything that is thy
neighbor's.
And all the people saw the thunderings
and the lightnings and the noise of the
trumpet and the mountain smoking, and
when they saw it, they removed and stood
afar off.
And they said unto Moses, 'Speak thou
with us, Mhm.
That's enough. They heard They heard the
sound and saw the thunder and lightning.
They heard them trumpets.
They moved forward. They mean That mean
they heard them, didn't they?
Yep. Well, let's let's go into
one other place. Let's go into Joshua,
sixth chapter.
We're going to read 1 through 4.
Then we skip down and read 8. Let me
know when you finish 4.
Okay.
Joshua, the sixth chapter,
verses 1 through 4.
It says, "Now Jericho was straitly shut
up because of the children of Israel.
None went out, and none came in.
And the Lord said unto Joshua, 'See, I
have given into thine hand Jericho and
the king thereof and the mighty men of
valor.
And ye shall compass the city, all ye
men of war, and go round about the city
once. Thus shalt thou do six days.
And seven priests shall bear before the
ark seven trumpets of rams' horns, and
the seventh day ye shall compass the
city seven times, and the priests shall
blow with the trumpets.'" That was the
end of verse 4, sir.
Okay, skip down and read verse 8.
And it came to pass when Joshua had
spoken to the people that the seven
priests bearing the seven trumpets of
rams' horns passed on before the Lord
and blew with the trumpets, and the ark
of the covenant of the Lord followed
them.
So, now had them seven priests with
seven trumpets, and they went
around Jericho
once a day for seven days, and they blew
them trumpets, every one of them.
So, yeah, you're going to hear the seven
trumpets.
Yep. That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question. Our next question with a time
check. Yes, the time is 8:26. Two Blue
asked, "In regarding to 1 Corinthians
7:10-16,
if a man and his wife were both
unbelievers at the time of their
marriage and divorced not due to
adultery, and the man later comes into
the truth, does scripture permit him to
remarry without committing adultery?"
All right. Seems to be quite a bit in
that question. It begins in 1
Corinthians 7:10-16, the guest caller
will take it from there.
Read it.
Okay. 1 Corinthians 7:10 says, "And unto
the married I command, yet not I, but
the Lord. Let not the wife depart from
her husband. But and if she depart, let
her remain unmarried or be reconciled to
her husband. And let not the husband put
away his wife.
But to the rest speak I, not the Lord.
If any brother have a wife that
believeth not, and she be pleased to
dwell with him, let him not put her
away.
And the woman which hath an husband that
believeth not, if he be pleased to dwell
with her, let her not leave him.
For the unbelieving husband is
sanctified by the wife, and the
unbelieving wife is sanctified by the
husband. Else were your children
unclean, but now are they holy.
But if the unbelieving depart, let him
depart. A brother or a sister is not
under bondage in such cases, but God has
called us to peace.
For what knowest thou, O wife, whether
thou shalt save Uh-huh. So,
So, now uh uh
They're talking about the unbelieving
now, right?
Yes.
So, now you said if both of them was
unbelievers
and they divorced,
are they in a sister case then? If the
unbelievers
leave, then the brother and sister is
not responsible. Isn't that what they
said right there? Yes.
That speaks for itself. That's all I
have to say.
All right. We'll leave it right there as
we move on to our next question.
Next one, Love Twice asked, "Are
Hispanic children of Shem or Japheth?"
Hispanic, Shem or Japheth, Brother
Julius.
They are of the children of Japheth.
Let me show you why.
Let's go to Genesis chapter 10. We're
going to read 1 to 5, Brother James.
Okay.
Genesis chapter 10,
1 to 5.
"Now these are the generations of the
sons of Noah, Shem, Ham, and Japheth.
And unto them were sons born after the
flood.
The sons of Japheth, Gomer and Magog and
Madai and Javan and Tubal and Meshech
and Tiras. And the sons of Gomer,
Ashkenaz and Riphath and Togarmah. And
the sons of Javan, Elishah and Tarshish,
Kittim and Dodanim. Go ahead.
>> By By these were the isles of the
Gentiles divided in their lands, every
one after his tongue, after their
families in their nations." After their
tongues, after their families in their
nations. So, Japheth, the progenitor or
the father of the Gentiles or what we
call the Europeans or white people,
slang for white people, are Europeans.
Central
Western, Central, and Eastern Europe.
Europeans and their descendants. So,
Hispanics are descendants of what you
call Latinos or Castilians.
Who And where are they today? They are
the progenitors of the people of what we
call Latinos. They spoke Latin, which
was their language. Uh uh
That's why you call them Latino after
the language, but they come out of
Portugal and Spain. Also on the European
continent. That's why it tell you these
were the isles of the Gentiles. They're
Gentile, divided in their lands, after
their families in their tongues in their
nations. So, therefore,
they come out of Castile, which is on
the European continent in Spain,
Portugal, in that area. Gentiles, not
Hamites, not Shemites. That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that.
As we continue to move on.
Moving on. Will Tate says, "In Galatians
5:21,
the word reveling means noun means a
noun. Reveling Revelings,
the action of participating in lively
and noisy festivities,
especially involving drinking and
dancing. Does this mean I'm not able to
drink and hang out?
No, it
don't mean that. It means that you have
to always keep the commandments of God
no matter where you go.
But let's go into that Galatians 5
and let's read that verse 21 cuz this is
going to answer your drinking part of
it.
If we Galatians 5 and pick it up at that
verse 21 cuz these are the ones that are
told that they shall not inherit the
kingdom of God. Go ahead, brother.
Envyings, murders, drunkenness.
>> Drunkenness.
>> Rebellions. It didn't say you didn't say
you couldn't drink.
But don't get drunkenness on you.
Some people, hey, they get that too much
alcohol and another spirit come on them.
Go ahead.
Revellings, and such like of which I
tell you before as I have also told you
in times past that they which do such
things shall not inherit the kingdom of
God. All right, so you asked about that.
Yeah, go right ahead, guest caller.
Just to read that 21 first verses
misrepresenting what
Paul is saying here. If you want to get
it all, you need to start at the 19th.
At 19, all right, let's do that. Let's
pick it up at 19 dealing with the works
of the flesh.
Okay.
>> Good catch. Go right ahead.
Now the works of the flesh are manifest,
which are these: adultery, fornication,
uncleanness, lasciviousness,
idolatry, witchcraft, hatred, variance,
emulations, wrath, strife, seditions,
heresies.
Envyings, murders, drunkenness,
revellings, and such like of the which I
tell you before as I have told you in
times past that they which do such
things shall not inherit the kingdom of
God.
Mhm. So that take
that cover more than just going out and
partying a little, don't it? Oh, yeah.
Yes, it does.
That's what I'm saying. Read it all, you
know, and then before you
come up with a solution.
Right.
>> That's all I have.
Yeah, we don't cherry-pick. We'll we'll
put it all on the table.
That's it.
Yeah. So, okay. Well, we'll go leave it
right there and we'll go keep right on
moving along then.
Uh yes, uh Kim Noel says, I need
understanding
in Isaiah 11 verse 2. I heard some say
that this is seven spirits
or one spirit bringing seven signs of
the spirit.
All right, then that Isaiah 11 and 2
dealing with the spirits. What you say,
Jerome?
Uh the key to separate is really talking
about
the word of God.
And that word of God encompasses all of
that that you read in that verse. So
let's go read it.
Um
Isaiah chapter 11 and 2.
Okay.
Isaiah 11 and 2 says, "And the spirit of
the Lord shall rest upon him, the spirit
of wisdom and understanding, the spirit
of counsel and might, the spirit of
knowledge and of the fear of the Lord."
Yeah. Yeah. Let's tie that
um with 1 Corinthians chapter 12.
And we're going to read verse 13 then
we're going to skip.
1 Corinthians 12 and verse 13 says,
"For what is it is for what is it
wherein ye were inferior to Uh-uh.
>> I'm sorry, that's 2 Corinthians. I'm
sorry. Uh 1 Corinthians
12. Yeah, verse 13.
All right, 12 and 13 says, "For by one
spirit are we all baptized into one
body, whether we be Jews or Gentiles,
whether we be bond or free, and have
been all made to drink into one spirit."
Through through the word of God. Skip
down
to verse 4 and read it to the 11.
Verse 4?
Yep. I will skip up to verse 4. Okay.
>> Read it to the 11, yeah.
Now there are diversities of gifts, but
the same spirit. And there are
differences of administrations, but the
same Lord. And there are diversities of
operations, but it is the same God which
worketh all in all.
But the manifestation of the spirit is
given to every man to profit withal. For
to one is given by the spirit the word
of wisdom. To another the word of
knowledge by the same spirit.
>> same spirit, the word of God. Go ahead.
To another faith by the same spirit. To
another the gifts of healing by the same
spirit. To another the working of
miracles. To another prophecy. To
another discerning of spirits. To
another divers kinds of tongues. To
another the interpretation of tongues.
But unto all these worketh that one and
the selfsame spirit dividing to every
man severally severely as he will.
>> As the Lord will. Yeah. Yeah.
One more place.
Psalms 147 verse 5.
Psalms chapter 147
verse 5.
Okay.
Psalms 147 and verse 5 says, "Great is
our Lord and of great power. His
understanding is infinite."
>> Yeah, and that understanding encompasses
the word of God. That's how he built the
heavens
and all that be in them.
Earth included. That's all I got.
Oh, yeah. Can I throw in something?
>> Yes, sir.
Don't you go and read that at the
uh
again.
This time you read the
uh
11 1 and 2.
Okay.
Isaiah 11 1 and 2. Okay.
Isaiah
1 and 2.
Okay, Isaiah 11 1 and 2 says, "And there
shall come forth a rod out of the stem
of Jesse. And a branch shall grow out of
his roots.
And the
And the spirit of the Lord shall rest
upon him, the spirit of wisdom and
understanding, the spirit of counsel and
might, the spirit of knowledge and of
the fear of the Lord."
Now we're going to let Matthews answer
this.
Go to Matthews 3.
I think it's 3 and 16.
Yeah, 3 and 6 and 3 and 16.
Uh 6 verse 3 and 16 says, "And Jesus,
when he was baptized, went up
straightway out of the water, and lo,
the heavens were open unto him, and he
saw the spirit of God descending like a
dove and lightning upon him."
So the whole thing is all, you know,
they're all kind of forms of spirit, but
the but you know, and and what Jerome
read was good.
However, this particular scripture was
talking about Jesus.
Yep. All right.
Yep.
All right, hope that answered your
question and as we continue to move on.
Uh yes, she also wants explanation
of Romans 2 verses 14 and 15. Let's go
to that Romans 2
and pick it up at that verse
and read 15.
And the guest caller will take it from
there. Romans 2:14 and 15. Okay. It
says, "For when the Gentiles, which have
not the law, do by nature the things
contained in the law, these, having not
the law, are a law unto themselves,
which show the work of the law written
in their hearts, their conscience also
bearing witness, and their thoughts the
meanwhile accusing or else excusing one
another."
And I the key here is that they had a
law written in their heart.
So he said they do the things of the
law, don't have the law, but they have
it. He just told you written in the
heart. Just like he do them, everybody
the same thing. He said he's going to do
the same thing to Israel. Go to Hebrews
8th chapter and read verse 10.
Hebrews
and
Hebrews 8 and verse 10 says,
"For this is the covenant that I will
make with the house of Israel after
those days, saith the Lord.
I will put my laws into their mind and
write them in their hearts, and I will
be to them a God and they shall be to me
a people.
Read now. However, we Paul put that is
come the same way with it we
we we that it goes with everybody else.
If you have the law in your heart, God
put it there.
That's all I have to say. Yes, thank God
for that mercy.
Oh.
All right. Sister Deborah, are we
walking into new territory now?
Uh yes, we are. We are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, February
the 18th, 2026.
Investment funds ask, "What are things
that should cause you to distance
yourself from a sister or brother in the
truth?
What are things that should cause you to
distance yourself from a sister or
brother in the truth?"
Bad behavior.
Bad behavior, sister.
Yes, go right ahead.
If they in the truth, then what are they
doing to make you distance yourself from
them?
I think you need to be more specific.
That's a nebulous question.
Mhm.
So, we'll uh leave that right there as
we go to the next one.
Next one. Malika says, "Someone told me
Revelations 13:10
means no white people will be saved
during the resurrection
and they get upset because I choose not
to hate white people the way they do.
Please shed light."
Let me handle that.
You know, people talk
You know, people talk like this that
mean they don't have no clue. How you
talking about in the revelation in the
in the resurrection? It's just like God
is just going to save Israel?
Let's back up to
Revelation the fifth chapter.
Revelation chapter five.
So, if you ever talk to you uh said that
to you, uh uh sister or brother,
that is foolish talk.
You're not going to say I choose not to
hate. No, what you do is you read the
book and you might find yourself
in in a uh uh uh
uh really looking at something. But
being that in the resurrection,
we going to deal with it. Let's let's
start at five and one first.
Okay. Revelation 5:1 says, "And I saw in
the right hand of him that sat on the
throne a book written and on the
backside sealed with seven seals."
Uh-huh.
And I saw a strong angel proclaiming
with a loud voice, "Who is worthy to
open the book and to loose the seals
thereof?"
Uh-huh.
And no man in heaven, nor in earth,
neither under the earth was able to open
the book, neither to look there on.
Okay. So, what happened? He wept. Read
the four and five, then we going to
skip.
And I wept much because no man was found
worthy to open and to read the book,
neither to look there on.
And one of the elders said unto me,
"Weep not. Behold, the lion of the tribe
of Judah, the root of David, hath
prevailed to open the book and to loose
the seven seals thereof."
Now, skip down to verse eight.
Continue.
And when he had taken the book, the four
beasts and four and 20 elders fell down
before the lamb, having every one of
them harps and golden vials full of
odors, which are the prayers of saints.
Read.
And they sung a new song saying, "Thou
art worthy to take the book and to open
the seals thereof, for thou was slain
and has redeemed us to God by thy blood
out of every kindred and tongue and
people and nation."
Wait a minute. How how many people did
that cover?
Everyone. Everybody.
Finish that.
And has made us unto our God kings and
priests and we shall reign on the earth.
That look like
he got some of his people out of every
one of them knowing songs, didn't it?
Yes.
So, how is it
how is it that
you going to say that we Israel is going
to be the only one saved?
I'm going to show you something to the
person that talked to you like this, I'm
going to warn them. Let's go to Matthew
the eighth chapter. Yes, sir.
And we going to start it at the uh uh
uh
Ooh, let's see.
Verse five.
Okay.
Matthew 8:5 says, "And when Jesus was
entered into Capernaum, there came unto
him a centurion beseeching him
and saying, 'Lord, my servant lieth at
home sick of the palsy, grievously
tormented.'"
And Jesus And Jesus said unto him, "I
will come and heal him."
The centurion ans- Oh, mhm. Now, this
centurion was a Gentile, okay? He's a
Roman.
Go ahead.
And then he wanted to ask Jesus to heal
his servant. Now, Jesus said what? I'll
do what? Verse seven.
Said, "I will come and heal him."
Go ahead.
The centurion answered and said, "Lord,
I am not worthy that thou shouldest come
under my roof, but speak the word only
and my servant shall be healed."
Uh-huh.
"For I am a man under authority, having
soldiers under me, and I say to this
man, 'Go,' and he goeth, and to another,
'Come,' and he cometh, and to my
servant, 'Do this,' and he doeth it."
When Jesus heard When Jesus heard it, he
marveled and said to them that followed,
"Verily, I say unto you, I have not
found so great faith, no, not in
Israel."
Wow. Wait a minute. He said his faith
This man's faith was greater than
anybody in Israel. Isn't that what it's
saying here? That's what it's Yes, it
is.
Keep reading.
And I say unto you that many shall come
from the east and west and shall sit
down with Abraham and Isaac and Jacob in
the kingdom of heaven.
Uh-huh.
But the children of the kingdom shall be
cast out into outer darkness. There
shall be weeping and gnashing of teeth.
Hey.
Now, outer darkness, that's the that's
the lake of fire, ain't that correct?
That is right.
So, he's telling you right here, people
going to come from east and west and all
kind of nations and they going to sit
down in the Father's kingdom with
Abraham, Isaac and Jacob and some of
these faithful Hebrews are going to be
in the lake of fire. Isn't that what
it's saying right here? Absolutely.
I I so I read this to whoever make feel
like that have a warning to you.
Whatever the Gentiles did to us and the
Hamites did to us,
they
were
they were operating as the hand of God
because the book was told you the Lord
is the one that brought this upon us
because of the
even about
both fathers.
So, you better take this as a warning.
But as far as in the resurrection, we
read in the fifth chapter of Revelation,
people out of every kindred, tongue and
nation,
they going to be made kings and priests.
That's during the millennium period.
And they going to rule
with the Lord.
That's all I got to say. And he told you
in Isaiah 56:1, "My house shall be
called a house of prayer for all
people."
Mhm. That's what it says.
Yeah. Hey, guest caller, can we read
that Acts 10:34, what Peter said in 35?
Read it.
Acts 10:34
and 35.
Okay, it says
Mhm.
Yeah, this is when he was bringing
Cornelius in, which he was an Italian.
Go ahead, brother.
Then Peter opened his mouth and said,
"Of a truth, I perceive that God is no
respecter of persons,
but in every nation he that feareth him
and worketh righteousness is accepted
with him."
Hey.
>> [clears throat]
>> That is correct.
Yep. But it's okay. But in case in case
this person that talking like this don't
believe in the New Testament, then go
read Judas where where the Lord in the
56th chapter where you see how his
house.
That's Isaiah 56. Isaiah 56, I'm going
to pick it up at verse six and seven.
Okay. Read.
Also, the sons of the stranger that join
themselves to the Lord to serve him and
to love the name of the Lord, to be his
servants, everyone that keepeth the
Sabbath from polluting it and taking
hold of my covenant, even them will I
bring to my holy mountain and make them
joyful in my house of prayer.
Their are offerings and they'll
sacrifice shall be accepted upon my
altar for my house shall be called a
house of prayer for all people. The Lord
God which gathered the outcasts of
Israel said, yet will I gather others to
him besides those that I gathered unto
him.
People itself don't.
Yeah.
Enough said.
Yeah. Whosoever will let them come.
All right. Let's move on to our next
question as time is a ticking, sister
Deborah.
Uh yes, Carolyn Jenkins asked in 1
Corinthians 3 verse 15, how is he going
to be saved? Please explain.
All right. Let's go in there 1
Corinthians 3
and verse 15.
And they want to know and how shall he
be saved.
Okay. 1 Corinthians 3 and 15 says,
if any man's work shall be burned, he
shall suffer loss. But he himself shall
be saved, yet so as by fire.
Open to the panel.
And you know, that that is not
complicated. He said if his works be.
Right. So now, if you repent
and stop doing the evil works,
then you going to be saved.
Yeah.
Read that verse. What verse did that did
we start at,
brother James?
>> That was 15 That was 15.
Back up and read verse 13. Okay.
Every man's work shall be made manifest.
For the day shall declare it because it
shall be revealed by fire and the fire
shall try every man's work of what sort
it is.
Go ahead. If any man's work abide which
he had built thereupon, he shall receive
a reward. Because revelation tell you
every man shall be judged by his works,
whether they be good or whether they be
evil.
And can we read um if it's all right
on James chapter 5 verse 19 and 20?
Mhm.
James 5
and verse 19 and 20 says, brethren, if
any of you do err from the truth and one
convert him, let him know that he which
converted the sinner from the error of
his way shall save a soul from death and
shall hide a multitude of sins.
Yeah. That's it. Man, he bought him
over.
Let dirty works
and start doing right. Yes, sir. Yeah.
>> See you then.
They say it in Ezekiel 18 chapter and
and Paul said it in Romans the 7th
chapter.
Yeah.
Yeah. Start doing right, you won't
regret it. Guaranteed.
Repent of your iniquity, be your ruin.
All right, sister Deborah, that time is
a ticking.
Yes, Miss Wade asked in Song of Solomon
1 verse 5, who is this person who is
comely and meaning what?
All right. Let's go to that Song of
Solomon's.
So you going to have Prov- Proverbs,
Ecclesiastes, and then you got the Song
of Solomon 1
and verse 5 and we'll go open up to the
panel.
And want to know who is this that says,
I am black but comely.
Okay. Song of Solomon 1 verse 5 says, I
am black but comely. O ye daughters of
Jerusalem, as the tents of Kedar, as the
curtains of Solomon.
Mhm.
Read 6 too, brother. There you go. Look
not Look not upon me because I am black
because the sun has looked upon me. My
mother's children were angry with me.
They made me the keeper of the
vineyards, but my own vineyard have I
not kept. Yeah. So Lord speaking.
>> Now this is just it.
Let's look at this this guy is black and
comely.
And his mother's children are angry with
him and made him keeper of the other
vineyard. Yeah. And the and the
while my own vineyard is not unkept.
Let's see who got a vineyard. Let's go
in the Isaiah the 5th chapter.
Yeah.
Now read that verse 1.
Okay. Isaiah 5 and 1 says,
now will I sing to my well beloved a
song of my beloved touching his
vineyard. My well beloved have a
vineyard in a very fruitful hill.
And he fenced it and gathered out the
stones thereof and planted it with the
choicest vine and built a tower in the
midst of it. And also made a wine press
therein. And he looked that it should
bring forth grapes and it brought forth
wild grapes.
And now, O inhabitants of Jerusalem and
men of Judah, judge I pray you betwixt
me and my vineyard.
What could have been done more to my
vineyard that I have not done in it?
Wherefore, when I looked that it should
bring forth grapes, brought it forth
wild grapes. And now,
Mhm. Let's see what happened now. He
planted everything right in his
vineyard.
Sure did.
>> Whoever this person
And when it brought forth and and it
brought forth wild grapes. Now let's see
what he going to do to it. Go ahead.
And now, go to I will tell you what I
will do to my vineyard. I will take away
the hedges thereof and it shall be eaten
up and break down the wall thereof and
it shall be trodden down. And I will lay
it waste.
It shall be It shall not be pruned nor
dig, but there shall come up briers and
thorns. I will also command the clouds
that they rain no rain upon it.
For the vineyard of the Lord of hosts is
the house of Israel.
And the men of Judah his pleasant plant.
And he looked for judgment and behold
oppression, for righteousness but behold
a cry.
Now who is the vineyard of the Lord?
Israel. The house of Israel.
That's right. And Judah is the pillar
plant. So So the one that said
uh
my mother's children were angry with me
and made me the keeper of the other
vineyard where my own vineyard is going
unkept. That show you going unkept
because of his behavior, didn't it?
Yes, sir. You know who he
said
He said, I am black but comely.
O ye daughters of Jerusalem.
So this is Jesus talking cuz you ain't
never dealt with nobody but Jesus.
So he is the one that's planted his
vineyard. Let you know it's Jesus. You
can read one other place. Let's go into
John 5 and 37. Saint John 5 and 37.
Okay.
John Saint John 5 and 37 says,
and the Father himself which has sent me
have borne witness of me. Ye have
neither heard his voice at any time nor
seen his shape.
So the one that said he's black but
comely, O daughters of Jerusalem,
the one that said that uh
his mother's children because he came to
his own. Saint John the 1st chapter tell
you that. And his own received him not.
And who is it that coerced uh uh
Pilate to crucify uh Jesus?
Israel. Israel.
So the vineyard is Israel.
And the
planner of the vineyard
is Jesus. That's all I got to say.
All right.
>> So that's
Jesus there who's black but comely.
Oh, yeah.
All right. We hope that answered your
question there, Miss Wade, as we move on
to our final question of the evening.
Yes, Earl Morgan asked for explanation
in Leviticus 19 verses 27 and 28.
Leviticus 19
verse 27
and verse 28 for our final question of
the evening.
So when you get there, brother.
Leviticus 19:27
and 28. We get this a lot. And I think
um
you can go ahead and begin, brother.
Ye shall not round the corners of your
heads, neither shalt thou mar the
corners of thy beard. Ye shall not make
any cuttings in your flesh for the dead,
nor print any marks upon you. I am the
Lord.
What did they do?
Pagan practice.
That's what the pagans
Well, we dealt with that thing with
round the corner of the beard. We don't
know what that mean.
But the other one mean you don't make
any cuttings in your body for the dead
for dead folks.
That's all. You know, like they have a
a hair had a custom.
Especially
among the uh
the nations, you know, they used to cut
themselves for the dead or put markings
upon themselves for the dead.
And they used to uh
you know what it's
do something [clears throat] with their
forehead from the dead. He said, "Don't
do that for the dead."
But it's for the
round in the corners of the beard, I
don't know what that is. That's all I
got to say.
All right. Deuteronomy 14:1-2.
Okay.
Read it.
>> that. Yeah, sure.
Deuteronomy 14
verses 1 and 2 says
It says, "Ye are the children of the
Lord your God. Ye shall not cut
yourselves, nor make any baldness
between your eyes for the dead. For thou
art an holy people unto the Lord thy
God. And the Lord has chosen thee to be
a peculiar people unto himself above all
the nations that are upon the earth."
So again, this is for the dead.
I'll have nothing to do with a haircut.
All right.
All right, Sister Deborah, time check.
Uh the time is 9:01.
All right. Well, we have ran out of
time.
And we'd like to thank everybody from
all around the world who joined us and
sending your questions. And we'd like to
say if you submitted a question we
didn't get to it, please don't resubmit
it cuz we will Sister Deborah will put
it in rotation and we will deal with
that question next week. So, until we
all come together again, we say be
blessed,
be safe, stay prayed up, and please feel
free to join us this Saturday at 12:00
noon for our third leg of black history
titled spiritual death and resurrection.
Brother James, close us out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our debts as we forgive
our debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil for
thine is the kingdom and the power and
the glory forever. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.